# Chaitanya Lotake

## **Full Stack Engineering Analyst**

Pune, Maharashtra, India Mobile No: +91 8149861874 Email: lotakec@gmail.com LinkedIn: <u>ChaitanyaLotake</u>

As a Full Stack Engineering Analyst at Accenture, I've spent the past 3 years specializing in .NET development. My expertise lies primarily in back-end technologies, where I've designed, developed, and deployed web applications that are efficient and user-focused.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Accenture, Pune, Maharashtra

January 2024 - Present

#### .NET Engineer

- Led the .NET team in solving production bugs for all client projects, achieving a 95% resolution rate.
- Worked with all the teams for providing build failure free production builds on every Wednesday.
- Worked on debugging production level bugs using Azure Application Insights.
- Worked with SQL team for any of the data related issue at production level.
- Implemented short enhancements alongside providing production support, resulting in a 25% improvement in overall team performance.

#### Accenture, Pune, Maharashtra

August 2024 - December 2023

#### .NET Engineer

- Implemented .NET Core solutions with CQRS for efficient command and query separation.
- Developed optimized gueries and read-side components, supporting microservice architecture.
- · Collaborated effectively in agile teams, facilitating microservice development cycles.
- Integrated Event Handlers for seamless Salesforce data sync using Azure Service Bus within microservices.
- Architected microservices for scalable, modular application design with CQRS pattern.
- Customized Zoom API endpoints for seamless integration with .NET applications reducing time taken
  to create the events by 50%.
- Used version control systems like Git, ensuring code quality and collaborative development.
- Developed and maintained database objects including stored procedures, triggers, and views, ensuring
  efficient data retrieval and manipulation.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

• C#

MSSQL

Entity Framework

.NET Core

Microservices

• Git

• CQRS

NHibernate

Postman

## **EDUCATION**

#### B. Tech in Information Technology May 2017 - June 2021

DKTE Society's Textile & Engineering Institute at Ichalkaranji

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate : AZ-204

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals: AZ-900

Microsoft Certified: Security, Compliance, and Identity Fundamentals: SC-900

Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals: DP-900

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### **Shared Success Catalyst Award-2023:**

Recognized for collaborating closely with clients, communities and ecosystem to deliver exceptional value.

## An award for Stewardship -2024:

"Performer of the Month - April'24"